Guide to the Robert A. Caro Archive [DATE]–2021 MS 3203
New-York Historical Society
- [TEMPORARY SERIES FOR LBJ NOTEBOOKS]
  - [no title; orange cover (small); mostly blank] (Box P108, Folder #)
  - [no title; pink cover with circles; mostly blank] (Box P108, Folder #)
  - [no title; purple cover; mostly blank] (Box P108, Folder #)
  - [no title; black cover (Mead); mostly blank] (Box P108, Folder #)
  - [no title; blue cover (Mead); completely blank] (Box P108, Folder #)
- Series IX. Working: Researching, Interviewing, Writing (published 2019)
- Series X. Other writings
- Series XI. Scrapbooks, 1952-2021 (bulk, 1974-2020)
  Thirty-one scrapbooks documenting Robert Caro's career, from his beginnings at the Horace Mann School, through his days as an investigative journalist for Newsday, and, ultimately, the publication of his seminal works on Robert Moses and Lyndon B. Johnson. While the earliest three volumes focus on his school and Newsday writings, the bulk of the scrapbooks—largely assembled by Ina Caro—hold a mix of materials charting the publication and reception of each of Caro's books to date. They include a broad mix of materials, from reviews and newspaper interviews, best seller lists, telegrams and letters (and in later years, emails), publicity tour schedules, photographs taken at signings and award ceremonies, invitations to dinners, and various pieces of ephemera, such as program brochures and place cards.
  The scrapbooks are filed chronologically, although there is some overlap in coverage between volumes. The contents of each volume are given in notes in the container list. Numbers in [brackets] preceding each item represent the pages of the scrapbook; in cases where a page contained multiple items, these are listed separately and assigned a suffix: "a," "b," "c," etc. While the volumes labeled "Scrapbook [A]," "Scrapbook [B]", and "Scrapbook [C]", are listed here, they are more fully described in Series I and Series II.
  - Scrapbook [A], "Robert A. Caro. The Horace Mann record. Horace Mann School, 1952", 1952-1953 (Box [XI-01])
    For description, see "Series I. Early writings, 1952-1955."
  - Scrapbook [B], "1964 Headliner Award Entry portfolio", 1963-1964 (Box [XI-02])
    For description, see "Series II. Newsday reportage, [date-date]."
  - Scrapbook [C], Nomination submission for Pulitzer Prize in Journalism for Newsday series "Suffolk: The Sick Giant", 1963-1964 (Box [XI-02])
  - Scrapbook 1, 1974-1975, 2000 (Box [XI-03])
    Spine embossed "1." Mostly contains Power Broker reviews and publicity.
    [01] "An announcement about The Power Broker.. .," Alfred A. Knopf.
    [02] Arthur Speigleman, "Robert Moses and Fall of New York," Majorca Daily Bulletin, September 21, 1974.
    [03] Paul Goldberger, "Book on Robert Moses a 7-Year Job."
    [04] Advertisement for The Power Broker, Newsday, July 19, 1974.
    [between 04–05] Handwritten notes, "Intro to PB," January 29, 2021.
    [05] Thomas Collins, "A Moses Chronicle With Some Hard Questions."
    [06] Stan Isaacs, "The Book of Moses," Newsday, August 25, 1974.
    [07] Thomas Collins, "Book of Moses Irritates Its Subject," Newsday, August 27, 1974.
    [08] Advertisement for The Power Broker, New York Times, September 4, 1974.
    [09] Joyce Wadler, "Bob Moses' Biography—Definitely Unauthorized," New York Post, August 27, 1974.
    [10a] Michael T. Kaufman, "Moses Rips Into 'Venomous' Biography," New York Times, August 27, 1974.
    [10b] Letters to the Editor, New York Times, September 6, 1974
    [11] Raymond Hall, "Robert Moses Controversy," San Francisco Chronicle, September 3, 1974.
    [12] Alfred A. Knopf Fall 1974 catalogue open to "The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York."
    [13] "News from Alfred A. Knopf" [press packet].
    [14] Advertisement for The Power Broker, New York Times, September 30, 1974.
    [15] Jack Patterson, "Moses: The crack in the monument," Business Week, September 7, 1974.
    [16–17] Eliot Fremont-Smith, "Moses Disposes," New York Magazine, September 9, 1974.
    [18–19] Peter S. Prescott, "Master Builder," Newsweek, September 16, 1974.
    [20–21] Philip Herrera, "The Book of Moses," Time, September 16, 1974.
    [22] Edmund Fuller, "Less a Moses Than a Pharaoh," Wall Street Journal, September 9, 1974.
    [23–24] New York Times Book Review: Power Broker, September 15, 1974.
    [between 24–25] Handwritten note "Internal Knopf memo."
    [25a] Unidentified newspaper advertisement for The Power Broker.
    [25b] "Memo regarding Doubleday ordering more copies of PB, 9/25/1974"
    [26–27] Mary Perot Nichols, "Robert Moses: Justice at last," Village Voice, September 26, 1974.
    [28–29] Richard Kluger, "Splendor in the books," New Times, January 11, 1974.
    [30] Publishers Weekly notice.
    [31] Christopher Lehmann-Haupt, "You Couldn't Fight Bob Moses," New York Times, September 9, [1974].
    [32] August Heckscher, "Mr. Moses and public works," Christian Science Monitor, September 10, 1974.
    [33] Donald R. Morris, "Robert Moses: cynical, arrogant—omnipotent," Houston Post, September 8, 1974.
    [34–35] Kenneth S. Davis, "The Master Builder," Newsday, September 15, 1974.
    [36] Wilson L. Barto, "Trenton Native, Husband Tell the Moses Story," Evening Times, Trenton, N.J., March 11, 1968.
    [37–39] Wilson Barto, "Robert Moses: The power broker is laid bare by a onetime Jersey newsman and his Trenton-born wife," This Week Magazine, September 15, 1974.
    [40a] Robert Moses, "Comment on a New Yorker Profile and Biography," Park East, September 12, 1974.
    [40b] Telegram from Edna and Al Feinstein to Caro congratulating him on The Power Broker, August 27, 1974.
    [41] Various best seller lists.
    [42] "The Critics are Saying... ," New York Post, September 28, 1974.
    [43] Sarah Gallick, "Some Gossip," Bookletter, vol. 1, no. 1 (August 19, 1974).
    [44] Robert L. Kerby, "Gotham Pharaoh," reprinted from The Review of Politics, vol. 37, no. 1 (January 1975).
    [45] Letter from Israel W. Levine, September 19, 1974.
    [46] Caro's interview schedule, as arranged by Alfred A. Knopf, August 30, 1974.
    [47] "Lesson in Use, Abuse of Power," Chatt[anooga?] Times, 1975.
    [48–49] Letter from Marie-Anne M. Evans, enclosing galleys of Peter Blake's review of The Power Broker from Architecture Plus: The International Magazine of Architecture, to appear in January/February 1975 issue.
    [50] Marshall Berman, "Buildings are Judgment," Ramparts, vol. 13, no. 6 (March 1975).
    [51] George Kateb, "Love-Hate Relation," [review of The Power Broker from unidentified, undated publication].
    [52] Publishers Weekly notice on increased print run for The Power Broker, August 4, 1975.
    [53] Partial article from an unidentified, undated publication.
    [54] Frank Kane, "Controversial Robert Moses: Massive Book on Master Builder," Blade (Toledo, Ohio), September 22, 1974.
    [55a] Jane Holtz Kay, "The Master Builder and His Works," The Nation, September 28, 1974.
    [55b–57] Murray Kempton, "Partners in the Fall of New York," More, October 1974.
    [58] Hunter Kaplan, "Caro's 'Power Broker': Moses in Manhattan," INDEX, UCLA Summer [Br—n?], August 1, 1975.
    [59] Jerry Tallmer, "Daily Closeup: The Definitive Moses," New York Post, September 27, 1974.
    [60–61] Myer Kutz, "For whom the bridges tolled," West Side Literary Review, vol. 1, no. 6 (September 26 1974).
    [62–63] Robert Cassidy, "Caro's Moses," Bookletter, vol. 1, no. 4 (September 30, 1974).
    [64] Shirley Gonzales, "Moses in the Promised Land," New Haven Register, September 15, [1974].
    [65] Justin Kaplan, "Moses Built Parks for the People and an Urban Empire for Himself," Detroit Free Press, September 22, 1974.
    [66] Anthony Wolff, "Dreams of Glory, Urban Nightmare," SR/World, October 19, [1974].
    [67a] Roberta B. Gratz, "A Party for 2 Park Builders," New York Post, September 23, 1974 (2 copies).
    [67b] Photocopy of invitation to dinner honoring Robert Moses and Laurence S. Rockefeller commemorating the 50th anniversary of the founding of the State Council of Parks, September 22, [1974].
    [68] Letter from Nancy [Colson?], Briarcliff College Colloquium Chairman, thanking Caro for participating in discussion of "The Continuing Crisis of the Cities in the Seventies," September 30, 1974.
    [69a–b] "Lessons From a Master Builder," Newsday editorial, September 23, 1974; with letter in response from George H. Mangravite, Miller Place, Long Island.
    [70] Herbert Mitgang, "Big Blockbuster on New York's Robert Moses," Showcase / Chicago Sun-Times, September 15, 1974.
    [71] Photographs [3] of Caro by Jack Pinto, Capital Newspapers Group, "for the Times-Union article by Muskal 'A chronicle of a master builder'," 1974.
    [72] Alternate photo from same shoot, Jack Pinto, Capital Newspapers Group.
    [73] Michael Muskal, "A chronicle of a master builder," Times-Union (Albany, N.Y.), September 22, 1974.
    [74] Michael Muskal, "A primer on 20th century power," review of The Power Broker from undated, unidentified newspaper.
    [75] David E. Lynch, "Author Calls Closing of Moses Pky. Section 'Significant' Event," Buffalo Courier-Express, September 22, 1974.
    [76] Bob Schlesinger, "Praise the Book of Moses, Praise the Human Season," Cleveland Press, August 8, 1975.
    [77] Joseph P. Fried, "Building of Battery Park City Finally Starts," New York Times, September 21, 1974.
    [78] George Vecsey, "Moses Is Honored on L.I. for His Service to Parks," [New York Times?], September 23, 1974.
    [79a] Invitation: "The Friends of the Albany Public Library / Present / Robert A. Caro / Author of / the controversial new book, / THE POWER BROKER, / ROBERT MOSES AND THE FALL OF NEW YORK / Monday, September 16—12:15 pm /.. ."
    [79b] Postcard to Caro, postmarked Albany, September 16, 1974, signed "Mimi" who "Enjoyed having you on Coffee Break. Thanks so much!!"
    [79c] Photo of Caro by Jack Pinto, Capital Newspapers Group.
    [80a] Peter Prichard, "Authorities were behind Moses' power," unidentified, undated newspaper.
    [80b] 3 photos of Caro in the TU [Times Union (Albany, N.Y.)] newsroom by Jay Reiter, published in following article.
    [81] Stuart Elliott, "The 'Power Broker' Watcher," Times-Union (Albany, N.Y.), September 19, 1974.
    [82] Letter from Murray Kempton to Bob Gottlieb, September 20, 1974.
    [83–84] Clippings of articles by Nicholas Von Hoffman: "Rockefeller Power," New York Post, [undated]; "Rocky and Moses," [unidentified, undated]; "It's not too late to veto Rocky," Hackensack Record, September 17, 1974; "Story of the Private Use of Public Power," Springfield Union (Massachusetts), September 20, 1974; "He's a Rocky New Yorkers Know," Washington Post, September 13, 1974.
    [85] "The Moses Challenge on Mass Transit... ," Newsday editorial, October 16, 1974.
    [86] Contact sheet of 4 photographs of Robert Moses by Arnold Newman.
    [87] Matthew Reed Baker, "The Power Broker," Brill's Content, April 2000 [piece on 25th anniversary of publication].
  - Scrapbook 2, 1974-1975 (Box [XI-03])
    Spine embossed "2." Mostly contains Power Broker reviews and publicity.
    [01a] Chris S. Zubof, "There Are Ways to Get Express Buses Into the City," Newsday, October 8, 1980.
    [01b] Photo of The Power Broker on display in bookstore window, August 1974.
    [02] New York Times Book Review best seller list, October 13, 1974.
    [03a] Jerrold Hicky, "The lit'ry life," Boston Morning Globe, September 7, 1974.
    [03b] August Heckscher, "Mr. Moses and public works," Christian Science Monitor, September 10, 1974.
    [04–05] [blank]
    [06] Victor Wilson for David Starr [not sure what to call this; telex? story sent by reporter, all CAPS, to news office?] (see scrapbook p. 13).
    [07a] "Honored Guest" pass, United States Democratic Convention, Madison Square Garden, July 12–15, 1976, for Wednesday, July 14.
    [07b] Fortune Book Club News, February 1975 [5 copies].
    [08–09] Robert Cassidy, "The house (and bridge and park and tunnel) the Moses built," Chicago Tribune, September 29, 1974.
    [10] Letter from Stuart Elliott, Gannett Rochester Newspapers, to Caro, September 19, 1974.
    [11a] Justin Kaplan, "The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York," Nieman Reports, [undated].
    [11b] William Ringle, "South Mall: Rocky's Peculiar Monument," [unidentified newspaper], September 18, 1974.
    [12a] Mary Perot Nichols, "Runnin' Scared," Village Voice, October 10, 1974.
    [12b] "Robert A. Caro's 'The Power Broker' Monumental September Knopf Publication," Catskill, N.Y. Daily Mail, August 9, 1974.
    [13] Victor Wilson, "Moses, the Czar. Massive biography reveals the man and his works," Long Island Press, September 15, 1974 (see scrapbook p. 06).
    [14] Gore Vidal, "Emperor of Concrete," The New York Review, October 17, 1974.
    [15] Profile of Gore Vidal from Vogue, December 1974, with photo of Vidal holding advance proof of The Power Broker.
    [16] Jack Newfield, "My Back Pages," Village Voice, October 10, 1974.
    [17] William Greider, "Senators Looking Into Rocky Gifts," New York Post, October 9, 1974
    [18a] Frank J. Prial, "Nelson and David Rockefeller Reported Principals in Secret 1968 Transit Pact," [New York Times?], October 10, 1974.
    [18b] Ronald Sullivan, "Byrne Asking Fiscal Data of Authority Appointees," New York Times, October 24, 1974.
    [18c] David A. Andelman, "'68 Transit Pact Disclosed," New York Times, October 24, 1974.
    [18d] "Ronan: The $625G Question," New York Post, November 18, 1974.
    [19] Photo of Caro.
    [20] Princeton Club of New York, Club Notes, vol. 7, no. 1 (October 4, 1974). Announcement of Caro lecturer for 1974–75 library series.
    [21] Princeton Club of New York press release for above.
    [22–26] David A. Johnson, "Monumental biography of Moses," Planning, the ASPO Magazine, October 1974. Includes interview with Robert Caro. [ASPO = American Society of Planning Officials].
    [27] Knopf August/September [1974] publishing calendar, listing The Power Broker on September 16.
    [28] Donald R. Morris, "Robert Moses: cynical, arrogant—omnipotent," Houston Post, September 15, 1974.
    [29] Herbert Mitgang, "Big Blockbuster on New York's Robert Moses," Showcase / Chicago Sun-Times, September 15, 1974.
    [30] Harold Lavine, "Moses' temple was called New York," Phoenix Republic, September 22, 1974.
    [31] "Surrendering to the auto: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York," Covington Kentucky Post, September 14, 1974.
    [32] Schley R. Lyons, "Robert Moses' Influence Reaches Far Beyond His New York State," Charlotte Observer, September 29, 1974.
    [33a] "Great Influence on American Cities—Robert Moses Was Master Builder," Youngstown, Ohio Vindicator, September 15, 1974.
    [33b] Joan Hanauer, "Robert Moses... The Most Powerful Man In New York," Chattanooga, Tennessee News-Free Press, September 29, 1974.
    [34a] Mary Ellin Barrett, "Cosmo Reads the New Books," Cosmopolitan, [undated].
    [34b] Ed Wellejus, "The Lure of Power," Erie, Penn. Times, [undated].
    [35a] Michael Muskal, "A primer on 20th century power," Albany, N.Y. Times-Union, September 22, 1974.
    [35b] Martin L. Gibson, "NY 'Emperor' Usually Wrong," Austin, Texas, American Statesman, [undated].
    [36] Howard Maniloff, "A Man Who Built Cities—And Warped Them," [unidentified, undated, Charlotte, North Carolina, newspaper].
    [37] Rod Cockshutt, "A Modern Moses Became Pharaoh," Raleigh, N.C. News and Observer, September 15, 1974.
    [38] Allan R. Talbot, review of The Power Broker in Citizens Housing & Planning Council of New York, Inc., Books, November 1974.
    [39] Mark A. Stuart, "Growing up a step ahead of Robert Moses," Bergen, N.J. Sunday Record, September 29, 1974.
    [40] Richard Jahnke, "The Man Who Built New York City," T.N.T. The Second Section of The Syracuse New Times, September 22, 1974.
    [41] "Surrendering to the auto: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York," Cincinnati, Ohio Post & Times-Star, September 14, 1974.
    [42] The Tarrytown Group Leisure Learning Weekend Program Schedule. "AFTER ROBERT MOSES, WHAT? an exploration of new ways of governing cities and institutions." November 22, 23, 24, 1974. With Special Guests: Gregory Bateson, Peter Blake, Robert A. Caro, Mary Perot Nichols, Jaqquelin Robertson, George Sternlieb. Tarrytown Conference Center, Tarrytown, New York.
    [43] Review of The Power Broker in Urban Growth, vol. 2, no. 17 [undated].
    [44a] Photo of Caro shaking hands with another man.
    [44b] Martin Levine, "Luncheon fare: Power of Moses, wit of Cavett," Newsday, October 25, 1974.
    [44c] New York Magazine, undated clipping with passage on Thomas J. Deegan Jr. underlined.
    [45] Newsday's Book and Author Luncheon program [2 copies], October 24, 1974.
    [46] James D. Dilts, "Robert Moses," Baltimore Sun, [undated].
    [47a] Review of The Power Broker from The Booklist.
    [47b] Advertisement, "Next Week in the Post: The Robert Moses Story" [a digest of The Power Broker].
    [48] Richard Reeves, "Democracy's Nervous Breakdown," New York Magazine, October 28, [1974].
    [49a] Stan Isaacs, "Rekindling the Fires," The Nation, [undated].
    [49b] Charles M. Cummings, "Massive Debunking of a Gotham Idol," Columbus, Ohio Dispatch, October 6, 1974.
    [50] Jacques Kelly, "This Moses Would Have Bridged the Red Sea!," Baltimore News-American, September 29, 1974.
    [51a] "Moses: The Masterbuilder," San Diego Union, September 15, 1974.
    [51b] John Raymond, "Robert Moses, Master Builder, Ruined a City?," Atlanta Journal Constitution, September 8, 1974.
    [51c] Larson Tipp, "The Power Broker," El Paso Times, [undated].
    [52] Daniel Berger, "Biography of Robert Moses Assesses Greatest of Builders On His Own Scale," Baltimore Evening Sun, September 27, 1974.
    [53] Murry Frymer, "Monument to 'The Power Broker'," Rochester, N.Y. Democrat & Chronicle, October 6, 1974.
    [54] James D. Dilts, "Robert Moses," Baltimore Evening Sun, September 22, 1974.
    [55] Russell Baker, "Man of the Year," New York Times, December 15, 1974.
    [56a] Francis X. Clines, "Carey Urges Quick Action On Naming of Rockefeller," [unidentified, undated newspaper].
    [56b] Thomas P. Ronan, "Carey Appoints Gribetz as His Counsel," [unidentified, undated newspaper].
    [56c] Linda Greenhouse, "Bus Moves Carey's To Albany Mansion," New York Times, January 1, 1975.
    [57a] Paul Gapp, "Robert Moses: Inventor of government in the shadows," Chicago Tribune, November 12, 1974.
    [57b] Paul Gapp, "Daley and Moses compared," Chicago Tribune, November 12, 1974.
    [58] The Library of Urban Affairs, January 1975, listing The Power Broker as alternate selection.
    [59a] Guy W. Gupton III, "The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York," Atlanta Gazette, [undated].
    [59b] R. E. Scott, "Painstaking Study of Machiavellian Motives," Fresno Bee, November 24, 1974.
    [60] Benjamin DeMott, "Moses & Memories," The Atlantic Monthly, December 1974.
    [61] Josh Freeman, "The Power Broker," City Star, October 1974.
    [62] Richard C. Wade, "The Power Broker," New York Times Book Review, September 15, 1974.
    [63a] George Mills, "Gripping study of Moses," Des Moines Register, October 13, 1974.
    [63b] Larson Tipp, "The Power Broker," El Paso, Texas Times, October 6, 1974.
    [63c] The Power Broker publication notice, New Yorker, September 30, 1974.
    [64] Richard Benke, "A Worm in the Big Apple. Bulldozing Neighborhoods For the Good of Whom?," Pasadena Star News, October 27, 1974.
    [65a] Hal Burton, "Another look at Moses," Newsday, November 8, 1974.
    [65b] William Greider, "Go down, Robert Moses," Boston Globe, October 20, 1974.
    [66–67] [blank]
    [68] Letter from Beryl Spector, Albany Public Library, to Caro, October 2, 1974, with photograph of Caro and [Spector?], and photocopies of reviews & notices from Albany-area newspapers.
    [69] Advertisement for The Power Broker in Book-of-the-Month Club News, January 1975.
    [70] Walter H Liebman, "The Robert Moses Saga: How He Rose—And Fell," Barron's, November 11, 1974.
    [71] Bill Marvel, "The Pitfalls of Power. Robert Moses' Career Is a Case Study in How Not to Plan a City," Silver Springs, Md. National Observer, October [5?], 1974.
    [72] Review of The Power Broker in B. Dalton, Bookseller, Merchandise Bulletin no. 310 (September 26, 1974).
    [73] Anna Mayo, "After Moses, What? / Last Week at Marienbad, Sort Of," Village Voice, December 9, 1974.
    [74a] Letter from Chester Burger, September 27, 1975.
    [74b] Letter from Margaret Snyder, August 21, 1975.
    [75] Al Troner, "Robert Caro, the Man Who Found Out about Robert Moses" [interview], and review of The Power Broker, The Statesman, [undated].
    [76] Gary R. Shroat, "The rise and fall of Robert Moses of New York," St. Louis Globe Democrat, November 23, 1973 [sic?].
    [77] Tom Fitzpatrick, "A literary lion with escape claws," Chicago Sun-Times, October 18, 1974.
    [78] Justin Kaplan, "Moses Built Absolute Power While Keeping Vision Limited," Akron Beacon Journal, September 22, 1974.
    [79] Paul Harris, "The Power Broker," El Paso, Texas Herald-Post, September 28, 1974.
    [80] Virgil Miller Newton, "Absolute Power Corrupts.. .," Tampa, Fla. Tribune & Times, September 22, 1974.
    [81] Frank Kane, "Massive Book On Master Builder," [unidentified, undated].
    [82] Frank Magiera, "One Man Powerhouse," Worcester, Mass. Telegram, September 15, 1974.
    [83] Peter Dreyer, "The Manhattanizer," [unidentified, undated].
    [84] Ralph Brem, "'The Broker' of Powerful Drama," Pittsburgh, Pa. Press, September 8, 1974.
    [85a] Charles M. Cummings, "Massive Debunking Of a Gotham Idol," Columbus, Ohio Dispatch, October 6, 1974.
    [85b] Judith Singer, "Lo! and Moses Made New York," [Houston Envoy?], October 18, 1974.
    [86a] Martin L. Gibson, "NY 'Emperor' Usually Wrong," Austin American-Statesman, September 29, 1974.
    [86b] William Greider, "Go down, Robert Moses," Boston Evening Globe, October 20, 1974.
    [86c] "The Power Broker," Nashville Tennessean, October 20, 1974.
    [86d] Advertisement for The Power Broker at Barnes & Noble Sale Annex.
    [87] Joan Hanauer, "The Moses era and its effect on New York," Syracuse Herald, September 29, 1974.
    [88a] Mary M. Baker, "Biographer can keep readers agog," Wilmington, Del. News, September 30, 1974.
    [88b] George Mills, "Gripping study of Moses," Des Moines Sunday Register, October 13, 1974.
    [89] Robert Taylor, "The Power Broker: New York's Incredible Robert Moses," [unidentified, undated].
    [90] Three photos of The Power Broker on display in bookstore window, August 1974.
    [91] Letter from Walton Onslow, October 23, 1974.
    [92a] Photo of Caro.
    [92b] Publisher's Weekly best sellers list.
    [93] [blank]
    [94–95] "Two Critics Choose the Best of '74," Newsweek, December 30, 1974.
    [96–97] "The Year's Best," Time, December 30, 1974.
    [98] Four photos of The Power Broker on display in bookstore window, August 1974.
  - Scrapbook 3, 1974-1976, 1979, 2006 (Box [XI-04])
    Spine embossed "3." Mostly contains Power Broker reviews, publicity, awards, and letters.
    [01] "Caro and Mayhew Win Book Award," Washington Monthly, March 5, [1975].
    [02] Letter, Mary Williams [Safio?], August 7, 1975.
    [03] Letter, Joel S. Freeman, President, Library Associates of Brooklyn College, informing Caro he is the recipient of their annual Distinguished Service Award for 1975, November 7, 1974. With invitation.
    [04] Letter from Gene M. Gressley, Director, University of Wyoming Archive of Contemporary History, asking Caro to consider placing his papers in their library, October 29, 1974. With follow-up since they received no reply, March 24, 1975.
    [05] Urban Writers Society Exchange, vol. 4, no. 4 (October 1974).